Guide to the Ulster County Collection 1666-1893 (Bulk 1700-1800) MS 645
New-York Historical Society
Ulster County Collection
1666-1893
New-York Historical Society
MS 645
1.25 Linear feet (9 boxes)
A collection of 185 items relating to the history of Ulster County, New York. Materials mostly involve land conveyance and boundary issues, but there are also a number of legal papers, financial items and military documents.
Provenance
Purchases: 1950 (Tomlinson Collection), and July 1923.
Donations: November 1923, December 1923, May 1931, June 1936, February 1939, May 1949, and others.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Historical Note
Ulster County, in southeastern New York State, is bordered by the Hudson River to the east and the Catskill Mountains to the northwest. Its early inhabitants were Algonquian-speaking Indians, such as the Delaware.
Missing Title
1614 Early adventurers came into the area to trade with the Indians for corn and pelts.
1615 Fur-trading post established on the future site of Kingston.
1652 Handful of settlers from Holland moved down from near Albany.
1653 Land purchased from the Esopus, a tribe of the Delaware Nation, for farming. Built village called Esopus, later Wiltwyck (Dutch for "wild woods"). After skirmishes with Indians, Peter Stuyvesant, Governor of the Dutch colony, brought soldiers up and built a stockade.
1669 Wiltwyck, now part of the English colony, was renamed Kingston.
1677 French Huguenots, under the leadership of Louis Dubois, founded settlement of New Paltz on 36,000 acres of land purchased from the Indians and patented to them by Governor Edmund Andros.
1683 Ulster, one of the original New York counties, was chartered to "contain the towns of Kingston, Hurley, and Marbletown, Foxhall and New Paltz, and all the villages, neighborhoods, and Christian inhabitations on the west side of the Hudson River, from the Murderers Creek, near the Highlands, to the Sawyers' Creek." Named for the traditional Irish province of Ulster, then under the control of James, Duke of York and Albany (later King James II).
1777 Kingston, the county seat, was the first capital of New York State. The state's first legislature, senate and supreme court convened in Kingston and George Clinton was inaugurated there as New York's first governor. In late 1777, British troops entered and burned Kingston, destroying much of the town.
1805 The community survived and Kingston incorporated as a village.
1828 Delaware and Hudson Canal completed. Kingston was the eastern terminus.
Source of Information: French, J.H. The Historical and Statistical Gazetteer of New York State. Syracuse, N.Y.: R.P. Smith, 1860.
Scope and Content Note
This collection is a compilation of a number of miscellaneous manuscript collections that relate to the early history of Ulster County, New York. One portion comes from the Tomlinson Collection, formerly owned by the Mercantile Library Association. Almost exclusively made up of land conveyances, this segment comprises a relatively small portion of the collection. The remaining material, from a variety of sources, includes land transactions but also legal documents, financial papers, military items and some correspondence. Certain Ulster County surnames frequently appear, such as Schuyler, Alexander, Provoost, Beekman, Van Cortlandt, De Peyster, Harrison and Colden.
Arrangement
See Series Descriptions for arrangement of each. The container list is at the item level for Series I, II and IV.
The collection is organized into four series:
Missing Title
Series I. Tomlinson Collection Land Papers (1697-1751)
Series II. Ulster County (1670-1893, undated)
Series III. Militia (1787-1809)
Series IV. Ulster County Oversize (1710-1778)
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
The New-York Historical Society has a significant selection of material related to the early history of Ulster County. Within the Manuscript Division, for example, is another collection made up primarily of 18th century land transactions and church papers - The Paltsits Ulster County Collection (Call Phrase: Paltsits Ulster County) - collected by Dr. Victor Hugo Paltsits. There are also individual manuscript items such as the following:
Missing Title
Account Book, 1736-1822- Call Phrase: BV VanGaasbeck
Land Surveys, 1767-[176-?]- Call Phrase: BV Gale, Samuel
Diary/Account Book, 1749-1780- Call Phrase: BV DeWitt
Patent, 1719/20, March 17, Ulster County (N.Y.)- Call Phrase: Y1720
The Library's General Collections contain a number of related volumes of which the following are examples:
Missing Title
Clearwater, Alphonso T., ed., The History of Ulster County, New York. Kingston, NY: W.J. Van Deusen, 1907. (Call Number: F127.U4 C6)
Fried, Marc B., The Early History of Kingston and Ulster County, N.Y. Marbletown, NY: Ulster County Historical Society [1975]. (Call Number: F129.K5 F82)
Sylvester, Nathaniel Bartlett, History of Ulster County, New York: With Illustrations and Biographical Sketches of its Prominent Men and Pioneers. Philadelphia: Everts & Peck, 1880 (Philadelphia: Press of J.B. Lippincott & Co.). (Call Number: F127.U4 S95)
Ulster County Historical Society, Kingston, N.Y., Collections of the Ulster Historical Society, Volume I. Kingston, Hommel & Lounsbery, printers [etc.] 1860-62. (Call Number: F127.U4 U4)
Van Buren, Augustus H., A History of Ulster County Under the Dominion of the Dutch. Kingston, NY: [s.n.], 1923.
The Print Room of the Library contains a number of related maps such as the following:
Missing Title
Cockburn, Will. A Map of the Division Line Between the Countys of Albany and Ulster, from the Mouth of the Sawyers Creek, 1765. (Call Number: M29.1.10)
The Library also has significant manuscript and general collections relating to the various families mentioned in this collection such as Colden, De Peyster, Schuyler, Alexander, Beckman, Van Cortlandt and others.
Accounts.; Real property -- New York (State) -- Ulster County.; Legal documents.; Kingston (N.Y.); Ulster County (N.Y.); Infanticide -- New York (State) -- Ulster County.; Correspondence.; Deeds.; Landowners; Maps.; Judicial records.; Colden, Cadwallader, 1688-1776; Cumming, Thomas; De Peyster, Abraham, 1657-1728; De Peyster, John, 1666-1711; Provoost (Family); Schuyler, Peter, 1657-1724; Smith, William, 1697-1769; Van Cortlandt (Family); Alexander, James, 1691-1756; Andros, Edmund, Sir, 1637-1714; Beekman (Family)
- Series I: Tomlinson Collection Land Papers (1666-1779)
  Scope and Contents note
  From the Tomlinson Collection, once owned by the Mercantile Library Association, this series is almost entirely composed of land conveyance documents. Box 1, Folder 3 contains an unusual item - a petition to the court in Kingston from Thomas Cumming who was indicted for treason, tried, convicted and sentenced to death. He is asking that the court recommend him to the Governor as an "object of mercy."
  The materials within this series are arranged in chronological order.
  - #1, "A Lyst of patents Granted from 5th December 1666 to the 8th September 1709 to Sundry persons. In the County of Ulster in the province of New York," 9 pp., 1666-1709 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #2, Deed by Johannis Wynkoop and wife to Henricus Beekman. 1 p., 1697 Sept. 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #3, Deed by Cornelius Fynhout and wife to Henricus Beekman. 1 p., 1698/9 Jan. 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #4, Deed by John Fortune to Grietie Cool for land south of Kingston. 1 p., 1698/9 Feb. 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #5, Deed by Broer Decker and wife to Henricus Beekman. 2 pp., 1704 July 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #6, Deed by Jacob Keyser to Jonas D'Langen for land in Marbletown, Ulster Co. 1 p., 1718 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #7, Deed by heirs of John Bigges to Samuel Cock to land in Marbletown, Ulster Co. 2 pp., 1723 Apr. 13 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #8, Deed by the Trustees of the Freeholders and Inhabitants of the town of Kingston, Ulster Co., New York to Frederick Seram for land in Kingston. 1 p., 1728/9 Feb. 28 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #9, Conveyance from Frederick Schoonmaker to Cornolis Hornebeck. 3 pp., 1730 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #10, Conveyance from Capt. Pawling to Gilbert Livingston for the halfe of 2/9 of a Tract of Land at Rochester. 2 pp., 1730 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #11, Conveyance from Grardus Hardonbergh to John Crooke. 1 p., 1730 Nov. 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #12, Conveyance from the Trustees of the Freeholders and Commonality of the town of Kingston to Gilbert Livingston. 1 p., 1730/1 Mar. 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #13, Westvael (Westphael) Bond. 1 p., Power of Attorney. 2 pp., 1731, Apr. 29, 1731 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #14, Deed by Johannis Westphael to Jacob Westphael for land in Kingston, Ulster Co., N.Y. 2 pp., 1732/3 Feb. 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #15, Johannis Stenbergh Release of a Mortgage to Albert Beem. 2 pp., 1733 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #16, Great Patent in Albany and Ulster counties. 2 pp., 1751 Nov. 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #17, Petition of Thomas Cumming. 2 pp., 1779 Sept. 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Ulster County (1670-1893, Undated)
  The items within this series have been drawn from a number of miscellaneous manuscript collections. All relate in some way to Ulster County, New York, whether they involve residents, properties, court cases or other elements. The materials are arranged chronologically. Box 2, Folder 4 contains items that are undated.
  Most of the documents in this series relate to land transactions or descriptions of boundaries. There are, however, various legal documents, financial papers (receipts, accounts, invoices), and correspondence. Some groups of legal documents provide a complete overview of specific cases. For example, there are oaths, notices, minutes, notes of evidence, jurors' findings and the judge's decision for the 1791 case of Schoonmaker vs. Woodworth and Credit (Box 1, Folder 9) and complaint, summons, attorney's description, affidavit of merits, notice of trial, defendant offers to settle and the plaintiffs' acceptance for the 1856 case of Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell (Box 2, Folder 2). In Box 2, Folder 4, there is an interesting document indicting an unmarried woman for the murder of her female child (#142).
  - #1, Copy (1744) of proceedings of a special court held at Kingston for purpose of determining the boundaries of Kingston. 2pp., 1670 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #2, Copy of the boundaries of patent granted to Lewis Dubois. 1p., 1677 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #3, Bounds of certain land patents in to David Provost (copy). 2 pp., 1684, 1694, 1703 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #4, Petition of the inhabitants of the County of Ulster to Sir Edmund Andros. 2 pp., 1687 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #5, Boundaries of Kingston. 2 pp., 1687 (1712 copy) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #6, Indian Deed to the Widow Rinmerig Quick for lands in Ulster County. 1p., 1700 Sept. 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #7, Copy of boundaries of land of David Provost, John DePeyster, Matthew Clarkson and Robert Sanders. 2 pp., [1703] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #8, Copy of boundaries of the town of Rochester. 1 p., 1703 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #9, Copy of boundaries of the town of Hurley. 1 p., 1708 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #10, Letters patents to Johannes Hardenbergh, Leonard Lewis, Philip Rokeby, William Nottingham, Benjamin Faneuil, Peter Fauconnier and Robert Lurting. 5 pp., 1708 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #11, Petition to survey land. 1 p., 1712 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #12, Warrant to survey land. 2 pp., 1712 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #13, Warrant to surveyor. 1 p., 1713 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #14, Land dispute suit. 1 p., 1713 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #15, Land dispute suit. 1 p., 1713 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #16, Memorandum re land demands. 1 p., 1713 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #17, Receipts. 1 p., 1719, 1725 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #18, Survey of land granted. 1 p., 1715 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #19, Copy of Letters Patent re tract of land to Palatins. 11pp., 1719 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #20, Warrant, 2 pp., 1721 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #21, Indictment, 2 pp., 1722 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #22, Receipt, 1 p., 1724 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #23, Indenture, Herman and Elizabeth Schunemans and David Provost, 1 p., 1724 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #24, Receipt. 1 p., 1729 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #25, J Daniel Macklester's Bond. 2 pp., 1730 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #26, T. Robert Kirkland's Bond. 2 pp., 1730 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #27, Boundaries of tract of land granted to Patrick MacGregory. 2 pp., 1720, 1732 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #28, Bond. 2 pp., 1736 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #29, Letter. 1 p., 1736 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #30, Indenture between "Henry Wileman of the Palts Kill in the County of Ulster Gent. and Rashell his wife of the one part, and Gualtherus DuBois of the City of New York, Minister of the Gospell of the other part." 4 pp., 1736 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #31, Court Papers, John More vs. Executors of James Scott, deceased. 2 pp., 1739 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #32, Copy of Sheriff's Direction to bring Executors of James Scott to Court. 1 p., [1739] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #33, Copy of Sheriff's Direction to bring Executors of James Scott to Court. 1 p., [1739] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #34, Sheriff's Direction to bring [Jurian Tappan] to Court. 1 p., [1740] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #35, Drafts of legal documents. 9 pp., 1741 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #36, Copy of Memorandum of Agreement between Windorts and Spratt / Alexander. 1 p., 1743 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #37, Davenport - Bogard land transaction. 1 p., 1743 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #38, Map. 1 p., 1744 Sept. 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #39, Deed. 2 pp., 1748 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #40, Indenture. 1 p., 1748 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #41, Indenture between "Even Toans of Ulster County and Province of N.Y. Physician, James Tuthill of the same place, Mariner, Ebenezer Sealey, Daniel Evert, Michael Jackson, Hezekiah Howell all of Orange County in the Province of New York Esquires, David Marvin and Henry Cass both of Orange County aforesaid Yeomen, Brant Schuyler of the City of New York Esq. and John Sackett of the same place merchant of the one part and Vincent Matthews and Joseph Sackett, Jun. both of Orange Co. aforesaid Esquires of the other part," 1 p., 1749 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #42, Indenture between John and Dorothea Roberts and George Harrison. 2 pp., 1750 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #43, Receipt. 1 p., 1750 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #44, Survey. 1 p., 1751 June (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #45, Land dispute. 1 p., 1751 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #46, Warrant to prepare Letters of Patent to Abraham Hasbrouck and others. 5 pp., 1753 Feb. 14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #47, Certification of errors in Letters Patent of Ann Mullender. 2 pp., (dated 1719) 1753 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #48, Letters Patent to Abraham Hasbrouck and others. 3 pp., 1753 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #49, Deed and agreement between Alexander and Gatehouse 2 pp., 1753 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #50, Receipt. 1 p., 1753 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #51, Receipt. 1 p., 1755 Dec. 22 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #52, Account. 1 p., 1757 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #53, Will and Power of Attorney, James Burns. 2 pp., 1758 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #54, "A List of prizes taken". 1 p., 1760 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #55, Warrant to prepare a draft of Letters Patent to Archibald McBride, James Crawford Junior, and others. 5 p., 1761 Feb. 6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #56, Warrant to prepare a draft of Letters Patent for Cadwallader Colden Junior and David Colden for 720 acres of land. 5 pp., 1761 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #57, Warrant to the Attorney General to prepare a Draft of Letters Patent to Samuel Fowler and Isaac Fowler. 6 pp., 1770 Jan. 6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #58, Indenture and survey. Fragment., 1770 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #59, Dr. Abraham Rose on account of James Latta. 2 pp., 1772-1775 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #60, Lease, Thomas Tredwell to Michael Wygant. 2 pp., 1772 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #61, Copy (typewritten) of Petition to William Tryon from "Charles Mair and William Anderson, disbanded Non Commissioned Officers, " 3 pp., 1773 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #62, Draft of Letters Patent to Oliver DeLancey and John Morin Scott for 1,200 Acres of Land in Ulster County. 8 pp., 1773 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #63, Bond, Thomas Smiley and William Miller to Jane W. Cobb. 1 p., 1775 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #64, Receipt. 1 p., 1777 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #65, Indenture between Robert Livingston and Philip Moore. 3 pp., 1779 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #65, Indenture between Robert Livingston and Philip Moore. 3 pp., 1779 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #66, Account, William Crop. 1 p., 1780 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #67, Arbitration of Robert and Andrew Thompson. 1 p., 1781 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #68, Indenture, Francis Kain. 1 p., 1782 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #69, Liquor license. 1 p., 1783 Dec. 29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #70, Liquor license. 1 p., 1785 Mar. 16 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #71, Receipt 1 p., 1787 Nov. 14 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #72 Schoonmaker vs. Woodworth and Credit- Oath of Schoonmaker. 1 p., 1791 Mar. 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #73, Schoonmaker vs. Woodworth and Credit- Notice to Daniel Woodworth. 1 p., 1791 Mar. 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #74, Schoonmaker vs. Woodworth and Credit- Notice to Benjamin Credit. 1 p., 1791 Mar. 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #75, Schoonmaker vs. Woodworth and Credit- Minutes of Proceedings. 1 p., 1791 Mar. 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #76, Schoonmaker vs. Woodworth and Credit- Notes of Evidence. 2 pp., 1791 Mar. 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #77, Schoonmaker vs. Woodworth and Credit- Jurors Findings. 1 p., 1791 Mar. 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #78, Schoonmaker vs. Woodworth and Credit- Jurors Findings. 1 p., 1791 Mar. 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #79, Schoonmaker vs. Woodworth and Credit- Judge's Decision. 1 p., 1791 Mar. 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #80, Deed of Bargain and Sale. James Nicholson, Francis Nicholson and John Vanderbilt to Francis Childs. 1 p., 1791 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #81, Petition. 1 p., 1791 Oct. 11 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #82, Lease, James Debrosses and Thomas Tredwell Smith. 1 p., 1793 Sept. 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #83, Indenture and Release. 2pp., 1794 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #84 Indenture. 4 pp., 1796 Feb. 15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #85, In Chancery: John P. Schott, Isaac Lloyd and Henry Sparks, Jun. vs. James Barton. 8 pp., [1796] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #86, Receipt., 1797 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #87, "Number of Taxable Inhabitants in Each Town in the County of Ulster according to the return of the Supervisors in the year 1796/97," 2 pp., 1797 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #88, Release for 5000 acres of land, William and Catherine Denning to Thomas Clarke. 2 pp., 1799 Mar. 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #89, Form Affidavit. 1 p., [1806] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #90, Receipt. 1 p., 1813 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #91, Mortgage, Frederick Leonard and others to Peter E. Ehnendorf. 2 pp., 1815 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #92, Protest of Note. 1 p., 1816 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #93, Note, Pleas / Returns. 1 p., 1817 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #94, Brief note. 1 p., 1817 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #95, Notebook, "The property of Thomas M. Holt" "Memorandum of Notes". 8 pp., 1819-1839 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #96, Notices of Court Dates. 1 p, 1819 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #97, Receipt. 1 p., 1819 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #98, Surrogate Certificate of the Granting of Letters Testamentary on the Will of Rebecca Bell to Michael Wygant. 1 p., 1820 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #99, Court case notice and acknowledgment, Robert Faulkner vs. David Oliver. 1 p., 1821 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #100, Letter, Classis of Ulster to Peter Elmendorf, Esq. 1 p., 1829 Sept. 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #101, Jeremiah Romeyn, License to practice as an attorney, Court of Common Pleas, Ulster County. 1 p., 1831 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #102, Summons - Ebenezer Cooley. 1 p., 1833 Oct. 14 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #103, Summons - Thomas Gill. 1 p., 1834 Jan. 22 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #104, Testimony - William Turner. 1 p., 1840 June 29 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #105, Testimony - Cornelius Quick. 1 p., 1840 June 29 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #106, Letter., 1846 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #107, Agreement between Leonard Lee and Thomas W. Chrystie. 3 pp., 1850 Oct. 14 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #108, Subpoena. 1 p., 1855 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #109, Subpoena. 1 p., 1855 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #110, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell, Complaint and Summons, Supreme Court, Ulster County. 2 pp., 1855 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #111, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell, Defendant's Attorney description of case. 1 p., 1855 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #112, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell, Notice of Trial. 1 p., 1856 Jan. 23 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #113, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell, Motion to Consolidate two cases involving same parties. 1 p., 1856 Jan. 26 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #114, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell, Affidavit of Merits (copy). 1 p., 1856 Jan. 31 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #115, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell Order of Consolidation. 1 p., 1856 Feb. 16 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #116, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell, Notice of Trial. 1 p., 1856 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #117, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell, Defendant Offer to Settle. 1 p., 1856 Sept. 29 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #118, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell, Defendant Offer to Settle. 1 p., 1856 Sept. 29 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #119, Henry H. Childs and John Dougherty vs. Thomas Cornell, Plaintiffs Acceptance of Offer to Compromise. 1 p., 1856 Oct. 10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #120, Cover letter for note payment, Isaac B. Henry. 1 p., 1857 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #121, American Express receipt. 1 p., 1857 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #122, Warranty Deed, William J. Coutant and wife to Zachariah Coutant. 3 pp., 1858 Mar. 27 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #123, Invoice / Receipt. 1 p., 1861 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #124, Renewal Notice. 1 p., 1862 Mar. 10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #125, Gas Bill. 1 p., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #126, Invoice / Receipt. 1 p., 1864 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #127, Invoice / Receipt. 1 p., 1864 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #128, Payment Transaction. 1 p., 1865 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #129, Payment Transaction. 1 p., 1865 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #130, Invoice / Receipt. 1 p., 1866 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #131, Transmission letter. 1 p., 1868 Feb. 29 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #132, Letter regarding share dividend from James Boyce to A. Anthony, Esq. 1 p., 1870 May 21 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #133, Order. 1 p., 1870 June 24 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #134, Audit and Payment Allowed. 2 pp., 1870 Aug. 22 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #135, Receipt. 1 p., 1872 Feb. 8 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #136, Subpoena and Deposition. 2 pp., 1874 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #137, Peace Warrant for apprehension of Michael Sullivan. 1 p., 1875 June 18 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #138, Letter. 1 p., 1882 Nov. 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #139, Letter. 1 p., 1884 Sept. 15 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #140, Letter, 23 September, 1884. 1 p., 1884 Sept. 23 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #141, Surrogate's Court Certificate of Appointment regarding Letters Testamentary on the Estate of James Patton. 1 p., 1893 Dec. 7 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #142, Indictment of Marya Boes for Murder of her Female Child. 1 p., [1721-22] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - #143, Survey of Land for James Alexander. 1 p., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - #144, William Smith Jun. vs. John Lewis - Counts and Pleadings for Domandant. 1 p., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - #145, Land Grant in Response to Petition of Thomas Ellison. 4 pp., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - #146, Survey map. 1 p., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - #147, Draft page from legal document. 1 p., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - #148, Letter. 2 pp., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series III: Militia (1787-1809)